Guide to the Norman Strung Papers 1966-1982
Montana State University-Bozeman Library
- Magazine Manuscripts, Series 2
  - Confirmed publication manuscripts, Subseries 1
    - "Roughing It: Putting on edge on garden tools", Mechanix Illustrated, September 1981 (Box-folder 21/48)
      p. 16+
    - "Rigging a river runner", Small Boat Journal, September 1981 (Box-folder 22/1)
    - "Best little trout streams in Montana", Sports Afield, September 1981 (Box-folder 22/2)
      p. 48
    - "Roughing It: Gathering wood the easy way", Mechanix Illustrated, October 1981 (Box-folder 22/3)
    - "Blue Skies and Waterfowl", Field and Stream, October 1981 (Box-folder 22/4)
      p. 52, written under pseudonym of Bart Yeager
    - "Whitetail Ways", Field and Stream, October 1981 (Box-folder 22/5)
      p. 102+, article and correspondence
    - "The Big One That Didn't (exactly) Get Away", Gray's Sporting Journal, Winter 1981-1982 (Box-folder 22/6)
    - "Roughing It: Stuff from scraps", Mechanix Illustrated, November 1981 (Box-folder 22/7)
    - "The bottom line", Outdoor Life, November 1981 (Box-folder 22/8)
      p. 54+, article and correspondence
    - "Ducks near the Big Apple", Field and Stream, December 1981 (Box-folder 22/9)
    - "Homemade Ice Fishing", Field and Stream, December 1981 (Box-folder 22/10)
      p. F, article and correspondence
    - "Roughing It: Gifts from homestead", Mechanix Illustrated, December 1981 (Box-folder 22/11)
    - "Eli Sly and the decoy deer", Outdoor Life, December 1981 (Box-folder 22/12)
      p. 66+
    - "The Brant are back", Outdoor Life, December 1981 (Box-folder 22/13)
    - "Trickle Trout", Field and Stream Fishing Annual, 1982 (Box-folder 22/14)
      p. 36+
    - "Successful duck hunting", Shooting Journal, 1982 (Box-folder 22/15)
      p. 46+
    - "The Whitefish of winter", Field and Stream, January 1982 (Box-folder 22/16)
      p. F-H
    - "Roughing It: Houseplants you can eat", Mechanix Illustrated, January 1982 (Box-folder 22/17)
      p. 8+
    - "The biggest game in waterfowling", Safari, January/February 1982 (Box-folder 22/18)
    - "South Bay Scooters: Ice boats of yesteryear", Small Boat Journal, January 1982 (Box-folder 22/19)
      p. 30-32
    - "How to Flag Wave Ducks to Your Dekes", The Hunting and Shooting Sportsman, January/February 1982 (Box-folder 22/20)
      p. 24+, for copy of typed article see Scotch Game Call: Hunting, 1979
    - "Roughing It: A fumbler's guide to glue", Mechanix Illustrated, February 1982 (Box-folder 22/21)
    - "Beating across Britain", Small Boat Journal, February/March 1982 (Box-folder 22/22)
      p. 15
    - "The Clearwater Connection", Field and Stream, March 1982 (Box-folder 22/23)
      p. 82
    - "Toad", Field and Stream, March 1982 (Box-folder 22/24)
    - "Roughing It: The $50 greenhouse", Mechanix Illustrated, March 1982 (Box-folder 22/25)
    - "Green Timber Greenheads", American Hunter, April 1982 (Box-folder 22/26)
      p. 18+
    - "Roughing It: Care and grooming of a paintbrush", Mechanix Illustrated, April 1982 (Box-folder 22/27)
    - "Roughing It: The art of picking a shovel", Mechanix Illustrated, May 1982 (Box-folder 22/28)
      p. 34+
    - "Backpack Hunting", Field and Stream, June 1982 (Box-folder 22/29)
    - "Montana-Wyoming horn of plenty", Field and Stream, July 1982 (Box-folder 22/30)
  - Unconfirmed publication manuscripts, Subseries 2 (Box 22-23)
    Manuscripts whose publication is uncertain. Often time accompanying the manuscripts is the title of the magazine but with no other information given. Most often just the manuscript is included. These manuscripts are arranged alphabetically because no date is available for any. The last seven articles in this subseries were ghost written by Norman Strung for Walter Cook. Their dates of publication are unknown and they are also arranged alphabetically.
    - "Angry waves", Outdoor Life Field Guide (Box-folder 22/31)
    - "Are You Walking on Thin Ice?", Outdoor Life Field Guide (Box-folder 22/32)
    - "Atlantic brant may open this fall", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 22/33)
    - "Baits for butts", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 22/34)
    - "Blow flies: Bad news for early Hunters", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 22/35)
    - "Body Language", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 22/36)
    - "Build a bird plucker" (Box-folder 22/37)
    - "Camp cooking tip", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 22/38)
    - "Deadly algea blooms in Montana Lake" (Box-folder 22/39)
    - "Decoy Patterns" (Box-folder 22/40)
    - "Do it yourself camper jack", Sports Afield (Box-folder 22/41)
    - "Don't drink the water", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 22/42)
    - "Easy Elk", Sports Afield (Box-folder 22/43)
    - "Easy ice fishing rig", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 22/44)
    - "Fish Hooks Man", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 22/45)
    - "Fish Kill in Montana", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/1)
    - "Florida Hunting and Fishing", Outdoor Life, ? 1973 (Box-folder 23/2)
    - "For a cooler cooler" (Box-folder 23/3)
    - "Fresh Fish without the ice", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/4)
    - "Getting the Range" (Box-folder 23/5)
    - "Gunstock Hand-Me-Downs", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/6)
    - "Greenland", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/7)
    - "Hats for sportsmen", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/8)
    - "The hidden danger in winter wading", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/9)
    - "High country hunting in the Rockies" (Box-folder 23/10)
    - "Hooks in your butts", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/11)
    - "Hot times ahead for the Madison", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/12)
    - "How to beat a bird's nest" (Box-folder 23/13)
    - "It's a real drag" (Box-folder 23/14)
    - "Hunting in Mexico simplified", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/15)
    - "The Last Straw", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/16)
    - "Little things mean a lot" (Box-folder 23/17)
    - "Mad for Snook", Outdoor Life (Box-folder 23/18)
    - "Montana acts to save the Yellowstone" (Box-folder 23/19)
    - "Montana Trout Study Yields Surprising Results" (Box-folder 23/20)
    - "Montana wilderness flat", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/21)
    - "The most dangerous place in the world", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/22)
    - "Offbeat waterfowling in Arkansas", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/23)
    - "Operation Hook Removal", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/24)
    - "Quack grass", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/25)
    - "Rivers of Plenty" (Box-folder 23/26)
    - "Rocky Mountain Grand Slam" (Box-folder 23/27)
    - "Salmon Fishing in style", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/28)
    - "Sheep going blind in Yellowstone", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/29)
    - "Solid sighting in" (Box-folder 23/30)
    - "A sportsman's guide to super glues" (Box-folder 23/31)
    - "Ten tips to take more ducks" (Box-folder 23/32)
    - "The tie that binds" (Box-folder 23/33)
    - "To build a fire", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/34)
    - "To tie a fly", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/35)
    - "Trophy sea trout in old New York", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/36)
    - "Trout aid in cancer research", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/37)
    - "Try troll-aid", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/38)
    - "The waterpack" (Box-folder 23/39)
    - "What's in a name" (Box-folder 23/40)
    - "Whitewater trout trips", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/41)
    - "Wilderness cleaner", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/42)
    - "Winter trout on the little red", Sports Afield (Box-folder 23/43)
    - "WWII menace in U.S. forests", Sports Afield Almanac (Box-folder 23/44)
    - "X marks the spot" (Box-folder 23/45)
    - "African/middle east update", Sports Afield, Walter Cook (Box-folder 23/46)
    - "African Update", Sports Afield, Walter Cook (Box-folder 23/47)
    - "Botswana Safari", Sports Afield Hunter, Walter Cook (Box-folder 23/48)
    - "European Trophy Fees", Sports Afield, Walter Cook (Box-folder 23/49)
    - "Southwest Africa teems with game", Sports Afield, Walter Cook (Box-folder 23/50)
    - "Texas trophy whitetail hunt", Sports Afield, Walter Cook (Box-folder 23/51)
    - "Tough tiger hunts", Sports Afield, Walter Cook (Box-folder 23/52)
- Magazine articles, pictures and correspondence about Norman Strung, Series 3 (Box 23)
  Published magazine articles either about Norman Strung or about something he wrote, such as a book review. Also included are published pictures that he took or that he appears in that appeared in a magazine. This series is arranged chronologically by publication date. Also included is correspondence he had with various editors dealing with articles not found in other series.
  - Cover photo, Fishing World, March/April 1970 (Box-folder 23/53)
    correspondence and magazine
  - Cover photo, Fishing World, January/February 1971 (Box-folder 23/54)
    magazine and correspondence
  - Cover photo, Fishing World, September/October 1971 (Box-folder 23/55)
  - News Clippings about Norman Strung, April 26-May 24, 1973; October 22, 1978 (Box-folder 23/56)
  - Cover photo, Fishing World, November/December 1973 (Box-folder 23/57)
  - Cover photo, Fishing World, September/October 1974 (Box-folder 23/58)
  - Photo p. 24, A Shooter's Guide to the 1974 Weaver-scope (Box-folder 23/59)
  - Cover photo, Fishing World, September/October 1977 (Box-folder 23/60)
  - Photo p. 22, Ducks Unlimited, March/April 1978 (Box-folder 23/61)
  - Photos p. 78, 84, 91, Sports Afield, April 1979 (Box-folder 23/62)
  - Photos p. 68, 69, Outdoor Life, August 1980 (Box-folder 23/63)
  - Photo p. 67, Outdoor Life, March 1981 (Box-folder 23/64)
  - "Book Review - Fishing the Headwaters of the Missouri", Gardner, Keith, Fishing World, March/April 1981 (Box-folder 23/65)
  - Cover photo, Small Boat Journal, January 1982 (Box-folder 23/66)
  - Correspondence, 1966 -- 1981; some dates unknown (Box-folder 23/67)
- Published articles with no manuscript, Series 4 (Box 24-26)
  Magazine articles that were published and had no accompanying manuscript or correspondence. They are arranged chronologically according to publication date.
  - "Something to Chew on", Western Outdoors, July 1967 (Box-folder 24/1)
    p. 42-43
  - "Leonard Grayson and His Flying Saucer", DARE, January/February 1968 (Box-folder 24/2)
    p. 28-29
  - "Outsmarting Sophisticated Trout", Sportfishing, April 1968 (Box-folder 24/3)
  - "Vest Pocket Fishing for Trout", Western Outdoors, April 1968 (Box-folder 24/4)
  - "Vacation Idea? Try Yellowstone Trout", Northwest Salmon Trout Steelheader, April/May 1968 (Box-folder 24/5)
    p. 24-27
  - "King Trout: The Cuttthroat", Sports Afield Fishing Annual, 1969 (Box-folder 24/6)
    p. 68-73
  - "A Place for the Family", Outdoor Life, May 1973 (Box-folder 24/7)
    p. 65-66
  - "How to Beat High Water", Outdoor Life, June 1973 (Box-folder 24/8)
    p. 55-56
  - "How Many Hours Until Sunset?", Sports Afield, January 1974 (Box-folder 24/9)
    p. 83
  - "Untouched Farm Ponds", Outdoor Life, May 1974 (Box-folder 24/10)
    p. 74
  - "Camp Cooking Simplified", Sports Afield, July 1974 (Box-folder 24/11)
  - "Turkey Time in Montana", Outdoor Life, October 1974 (Box-folder 24/12)
    p. 57-58
  - "Don't Take Rocks for Granite", and "Quick Camper Removal", Sports Afield, October 1974 (Box-folder 24/13)
    p. 106, 107
  - "Canepoling for Whitefish", Outdoor Life, December 1974 (Box-folder 24/14)
    p. 33-34
  - "High Country Reverie", Colorado, September/October 1975 (Box-folder 25/1)
    p. 60-64+
  - "Don't Take Rocks for Granite", copy of this article also appeared in Sports Afield, October 1974 (Box-folder 25/2)
    "Many Uses of the Inner Tube", "Quick Camper Removal", copy of this article also appeared in Sports Afield, October 1974, Sports Afield Almanac, 1976, p. 94, 43, 95
  - "Float for Your Fish", Field and Stream Fishing Annual, 1977 (Box-folder 25/3)
    p. 88-91
  - "How to use game calls on ducks", Scotch Game Call Hunting Annual, 1977 (Box-folder 25/4)
    p. 16-18+
  - "Where, How To Scratch the Montana Trout Itch", Outdoor Life, May 1977 (Box-folder 25/5)
  - "Furbish Lousewort Loses Lease on Life", Sports Afield, August 1977 (Box-folder 25/6)
  - "Getting a Grip on Things", "Super Varnish Remover", Sports Afield, December 1977 (Box-folder 25/7)
    p. 70, 66
  - "Ideas for using scrap lumber", The Family Handyman, February 1978 (Box-folder 25/8)
  - "Montana Shooting? Try Prairie Dogs, Chucks", Outdoor Life, March 1978 (Box-folder 25/9)
  - "Lower Madison is Tops for Early Season Trout", Outdoor Life, April 1978 (Box-folder 25/10)
  - "The Offer Trout Can't Refuse", Field and Stream, November 1978 (Box-folder 25/11)
    p. 39+
  - "Trailer Trick", Sports Afield, April 1979 (Box-folder 25/12)
  - "No Limits on Sheep Hunting in Montana", Sports Afield, July 1979 (Box-folder 25/13)
  - "Decoy Economy", Sports Afield, November 1979 (Box-folder 26/1)
  - "Reflections on a Trout Stream", Outdoor Life, February 1980 (Box-folder 26/2)
    p. 60+ no copy of article in magazine available
  - "Dangerous Courtesy", Sports Afield, March 1980 (Box-folder 26/3)
  - "Try Weekending for Montana's Trout", Sports Afield, June 1980 (Box-folder 26/4)
  - "Better-Tasting Venison", Sports Afield, October 1980 (Box-folder 26/5)
  - "How to use game calls on ducks", The Hunting and Shooting Sportsman, November/December 1981 (Box-folder 25/6)
    p. 16-17+, article also appeared in Scotch Game Call Hunting Annual, 1977, p. 16-18+
  - "Trophy Trout in Montana's Big Horn", Sports Afield, January 1982 (Box-folder 25/7)
    p. 65